<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-03-05T19:17:15+01:00</updated><id>http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/feed.xml</id><title type="html">SPP2137 Skyrmionics</title><subtitle>Topological Spin Phenomena in Real-Space for Applications</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Young Researchers’ Retreat 2024</title><link href="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/SPP-retreat-meeting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Young Researchers’ Retreat 2024" /><published>2024-01-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-01-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/SPP-retreat-meeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/SPP-retreat-meeting/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="21---25-april-2024-dietmannsried">21 - 25 April 2024, Dietmannsried</h4>

<p><strong>Organizers:</strong> <a href="https://www.ph.tum.de/about/people/vcard/3B40DAE77B1ACCCB/?language=en/">Aisha Aqeel</a>, <a href="https://www.uni-due.de/physik/twist/alessandro_pignedoli.php">Alessandro Pignedoli</a>, <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/janmasell/main">Jan Masell</a>, <a href="https://www.klaeui-lab.physik.uni-mainz.de/people/">Mona Bhukta</a>, and <a href="https://www.sinova-group.physik.uni-mainz.de/team/venkata-krishna-bharadwaj/">Venkata Krishna Bharadwaj</a>.</p>

<p>This retreat meeting is aimed at young researchers of the priority program SPP2137 and will pursue three objectives:</p>
<ol>
<li> building a network among young researchers interested in skyrmionics, namely students, PhD candidates, postdocs, as well as junior group leaders, </li>
<li> broadening the knowledge of the current status and the future of research on skyrmionics, and </li>
<li> promoting individual communication and research skills. </li>
</ol>

<p>The retreat will start on April 21 with dinner at 6 pm and will end on April 25 after lunch at around 1:30 pm. The schedule will be uploaded shortly.</p>

<p>The retreat will take place in the seminar rooms of <a href="https://www.dasflaxhotels.com/index.php/de/"><em>das flax allgäu</em></a>, Schlosserstr. 4, 87463 Dietmannsried. Participants are requested to arrange travel themselves. Onsite accommodation and meals will be provided by the SPP.</p>

<h3 id="how-to-apply">How to apply:</h3>
<p>To register for the retreat, please send the application form (<a href="/assets/2024-01-22-SPP2137-Application-Form.pdf">example</a>) by <strong>15.03.2024</strong> to <a href="mailto:alessandro.pignedoli@uni-due.de">Alessandro Pignedoli</a>. All participants are requested to contribute a poster. In addition to your poster, you can apply for a contributed talk (15 ~ 20 mins).</p>

<h3 id="invited-speakers">Invited speakers</h3>
<p>Prof. Istvan Kezsmarki (Uni. Augsburg)</p>

<p>Dr. Ankit Sharma (Attocube Systems AG)</p>

<p>Prof. Ulrich Nowak (Uni. Konstanz)</p>

<p>Dr. Vincent Cros (Laboratoire Albert Fert)</p>

<p>TT. - Prof.  Dr.-Ing. Yolita Eggeler (KIT, Karlsruhe)</p>

<p>Dr. Christina Psaroudaki (LPENS, Paris)</p>

<h3 id="young-researcher-speakers">Young researcher speakers</h3>
<p>Dr. Denis Mettus (TU Munich)</p>

<p>Kai Litzius (Uni. Augsburg)</p>

<p>Thomas Winkler (JGU, Mainz)</p>

<p>Valentin Ahrens (TU Munich)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="activities" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[21 - 25 April 2024, Dietmannsried Organizers: Aisha Aqeel, Alessandro Pignedoli, Jan Masell, Mona Bhukta, and Venkata Krishna Bharadwaj. This retreat meeting is aimed at young researchers of the priority program SPP2137 and will pursue three objectives: building a network among young researchers interested in skyrmionics, namely students, PhD candidates, postdocs, as well as junior group leaders, broadening the knowledge of the current status and the future of research on skyrmionics, and promoting individual communication and research skills. The retreat will start on April 21 with dinner at 6 pm and will end on April 25 after lunch at around 1:30 pm. The schedule will be uploaded shortly. The retreat will take place in the seminar rooms of das flax allgäu, Schlosserstr. 4, 87463 Dietmannsried. Participants are requested to arrange travel themselves. Onsite accommodation and meals will be provided by the SPP. How to apply: To register for the retreat, please send the application form (example) by 15.03.2024 to Alessandro Pignedoli. All participants are requested to contribute a poster. In addition to your poster, you can apply for a contributed talk (15 ~ 20 mins). Invited speakers Prof. Istvan Kezsmarki (Uni. Augsburg) Dr. Ankit Sharma (Attocube Systems AG) Prof. Ulrich Nowak (Uni. Konstanz) Dr. Vincent Cros (Laboratoire Albert Fert) TT. - Prof. Dr.-Ing. Yolita Eggeler (KIT, Karlsruhe) Dr. Christina Psaroudaki (LPENS, Paris) Young researcher speakers Dr. Denis Mettus (TU Munich) Kai Litzius (Uni. Augsburg) Thomas Winkler (JGU, Mainz) Valentin Ahrens (TU Munich)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Workshop on Numerical Methods for Topological Magnetic Textures</title><link href="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Workshop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Workshop on Numerical Methods for Topological Magnetic Textures" /><published>2023-10-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-10-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Workshop/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="28--29-november-2023-karlsruhe">28 &amp; 29 November 2023, Karlsruhe</h4>

<p>A workshop on Numerical Methods for Topological Magnetic Textures took place on 28 and 29 November 2023 in the Gastdozentenhaus of the Karlruher Institut für Technologie (KIT).</p>

<p>The workshop served as a platform for researchers who develop micromagnetic and atomistic simulation codes that are specifically designed for applications in the context of topological magnetic textures.</p>

<p>The workshop was organized by Jan Masell (Karlsruhe) and Hans Fangohr (Hamburg).</p>

<p>Further information may be found at the following <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/janmasell/main/workshop-numerical-magnetism">website</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="past" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[28 &amp; 29 November 2023, Karlsruhe A workshop on Numerical Methods for Topological Magnetic Textures took place on 28 and 29 November 2023 in the Gastdozentenhaus of the Karlruher Institut für Technologie (KIT). The workshop served as a platform for researchers who develop micromagnetic and atomistic simulation codes that are specifically designed for applications in the context of topological magnetic textures. The workshop was organized by Jan Masell (Karlsruhe) and Hans Fangohr (Hamburg). Further information may be found at the following website.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retreat Meeting 2023</title><link href="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Retreat-Meeting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retreat Meeting 2023" /><published>2023-05-02T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-05-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Retreat-Meeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Retreat-Meeting/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="13---15-september-2023-hamburg">13 - 15 September 2023, Hamburg</h4>

<p>A retreat meeting of the priority program SPP2137 took place from 13 through 15 September 2023 on the premises of the Bucerius Law School in Hamburg. Both oral and poster presentations were given.</p>

<p>The retreat meeting was organized by Kirsten von Bergmann (Hamburg) and Stefan Heinze (Kiel).</p>

<p>The program of the retreat meeting may be found <a href="/assets/2023-07-30-SPP2137-Registration-retreat-program.pdf">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="past" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[13 - 15 September 2023, Hamburg A retreat meeting of the priority program SPP2137 took place from 13 through 15 September 2023 on the premises of the Bucerius Law School in Hamburg. Both oral and poster presentations were given. The retreat meeting was organized by Kirsten von Bergmann (Hamburg) and Stefan Heinze (Kiel). The program of the retreat meeting may be found here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Young researcher mobility grants</title><link href="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/mobility/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Young researcher mobility grants" /><published>2023-04-03T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-04-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/mobility</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/mobility/"><![CDATA[<p>To promote synergies between the research groups contributing to the priority program SPP2137, dedicated financial support is available for travel expenses and accommodation of young researchers (students, PhD students, and postdocs).</p>

<p>The financial support serves to promote collaborations, training, and transfer of know-how by enabling visits in Germany. Visits must involve at least one of the participating groups of the SPP (<a href="https://gepris.dfg.de/gepris/projekt/360506545">see list</a>). No funding can be made available for the participation of conferences or workshops, or visits of groups outside Germany.</p>

<p>Visits must be completed by <strong>30 October 2023</strong> at the latest. The financial support is provided in the form of a reimbursement through the coordination project following completion of the visit. Claims for reimbursement should be filed by <strong>1 December 2023</strong> at the latest.</p>

<p>To apply, please send an informal request for approval to the head of the steering committee (<a href="mailto:Christian.Pfleiderer@frm2.tum.de">Prof. Christian Pfleiderer</a>) stating:</p>
<ul>
  <li>name of young researcher (applicant)</li>
  <li>names and affiliations of heads of groups involved (host and visitor)</li>
  <li>purpose of visit</li>
  <li>estimate of expected expenses</li>
</ul>

<p>The allocation of funds will be on a “first come – first serve” basis until the budget foreseen for this activity has been spent.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="hidden" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[To promote synergies between the research groups contributing to the priority program SPP2137, dedicated financial support is available for travel expenses and accommodation of young researchers (students, PhD students, and postdocs). The financial support serves to promote collaborations, training, and transfer of know-how by enabling visits in Germany. Visits must involve at least one of the participating groups of the SPP (see list). No funding can be made available for the participation of conferences or workshops, or visits of groups outside Germany. Visits must be completed by 30 October 2023 at the latest. The financial support is provided in the form of a reimbursement through the coordination project following completion of the visit. Claims for reimbursement should be filed by 1 December 2023 at the latest. To apply, please send an informal request for approval to the head of the steering committee (Prof. Christian Pfleiderer) stating: name of young researcher (applicant) names and affiliations of heads of groups involved (host and visitor) purpose of visit estimate of expected expenses The allocation of funds will be on a “first come – first serve” basis until the budget foreseen for this activity has been spent.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Young Researchers’ Retreat 2022</title><link href="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/SPP-retreat-meeting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Young Researchers’ Retreat 2022" /><published>2022-06-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-06-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/SPP-retreat-meeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/SPP-retreat-meeting/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="12---15-september-2022-annweiler-am-trifels">12 - 15 September 2022, Annweiler am Trifels</h4>

<p>A retreat aimed at young researchers of the priority program SPP2137 took place from 12 - 15 September 2022 at Kurhaus Trifels in Annweiler am Trifels.</p>

<p>The retreat was supported by the DFG priority program on Skyrmionics. It pursued three objectives:</p>

<ol>
  <li>building a network among young researchers interested in Skyrmionics, namely students, PhD candidates, postdocs, as well as junior group leaders,</li>
  <li>broadening the knowledge of the current status and the future of research on skyrmionics, and</li>
  <li>promoting individual communication and research skills.</li>
</ol>

<p>The meeting featured scientific tutorials, contributed talks, poster sessions, and personal skills training. It was organized by Maria Azhar, Sebastián Díaz, Jonathan Kipp, and Sopheak Sorn.</p>

<p>Final schedule: <a href="/assets/2022-06-20-SPP2137-Final-Program.pdf">pdf</a></p>

<p><img src="/assets/2022-06-20-SPP2137-group-picture.jpg" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="past" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[12 - 15 September 2022, Annweiler am Trifels A retreat aimed at young researchers of the priority program SPP2137 took place from 12 - 15 September 2022 at Kurhaus Trifels in Annweiler am Trifels. The retreat was supported by the DFG priority program on Skyrmionics. It pursued three objectives: building a network among young researchers interested in Skyrmionics, namely students, PhD candidates, postdocs, as well as junior group leaders, broadening the knowledge of the current status and the future of research on skyrmionics, and promoting individual communication and research skills. The meeting featured scientific tutorials, contributed talks, poster sessions, and personal skills training. It was organized by Maria Azhar, Sebastián Díaz, Jonathan Kipp, and Sopheak Sorn. Final schedule: pdf]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retreat Meeting 2021</title><link href="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/SPP-retreat-meeting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retreat Meeting 2021" /><published>2021-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/SPP-retreat-meeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/SPP-retreat-meeting/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="13---15-october-2021-bad-honnef">13 - 15 October 2021, Bad Honnef</h4>

<p>A retreat meeting of the priority program SPP2137 took place from 13 through 15 October 2021 at the Physik-Zentrum in Bad Honnef. The meeting was “hybrid” and permitted onsite as well as online participation. Both oral and poster presentations were given.</p>

<p>The program may be found <a href="/assets/2021-08-15-SPP2137-retreat-Program.pdf">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="past" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[13 - 15 October 2021, Bad Honnef A retreat meeting of the priority program SPP2137 took place from 13 through 15 October 2021 at the Physik-Zentrum in Bad Honnef. The meeting was “hybrid” and permitted onsite as well as online participation. Both oral and poster presentations were given. The program may be found here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Call for Proposals 2020</title><link href="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Call-for-proposals/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Call for Proposals 2020" /><published>2020-10-16T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-10-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Call-for-proposals</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Call-for-proposals/"><![CDATA[<p>The call for proposals for the second funding period closed on 16 November 2020.
Proposals were reviewed online on 4 &amp; 5 March 2021. The official call for the proposals may be found <a href="https://www.dfg.de/foerderung/info_wissenschaft/2020/info_wissenschaft_20_55/">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="past" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The call for proposals for the second funding period closed on 16 November 2020. Proposals were reviewed online on 4 &amp; 5 March 2021. The official call for the proposals may be found here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retreat &amp;amp; Networking Meeting 2020</title><link href="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Retreat-Networking-Meeting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retreat &amp;amp; Networking Meeting 2020" /><published>2020-09-03T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-09-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Retreat-Networking-Meeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Retreat-Networking-Meeting/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="3--4-september-2020-bad-honnef">3 &amp; 4 September 2020, Bad Honnef</h4>

<p>A retreat and networking meeting of the priority program SPP2137 took place on 3 &amp; 4 September 2020 at the Physik-Zentrum in Bad Honnef. The meeting was “hybrid”, with ~20 participants onsite and ~85 participants offsite. The program of the meeting may be found <a href="/assets/2020-09-01-SPP2137-retreat.pdf">here</a>.</p>

<p>Presentations of the Network meeting 2020</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="/assets/2020-09-05-SPP2137-presentation-EReister.pdf">Presentation of E. Reister</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/2020-09-05-SPP2137-presentation-CPfleiderer.pdf">Presentation of C. Pfleiderer</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="past" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[3 &amp; 4 September 2020, Bad Honnef A retreat and networking meeting of the priority program SPP2137 took place on 3 &amp; 4 September 2020 at the Physik-Zentrum in Bad Honnef. The meeting was “hybrid”, with ~20 participants onsite and ~85 participants offsite. The program of the meeting may be found here. Presentations of the Network meeting 2020 Presentation of E. Reister Presentation of C. Pfleiderer]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Corona-Related Cancellations 2020</title><link href="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Corona-related-cancellation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Corona-Related Cancellations 2020" /><published>2020-08-04T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Corona-related-cancellation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/Corona-related-cancellation/"><![CDATA[<p>For 2020 a retreat meeting at Bad Honnef (26 &amp; 27 March 2020), as well as an international autumn school and international conference at Kloster Seeon (2 - 6 November 2020), were planned that had to be cancelled.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="past" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[For 2020 a retreat meeting at Bad Honnef (26 &amp; 27 March 2020), as well as an international autumn school and international conference at Kloster Seeon (2 - 6 November 2020), were planned that had to be cancelled.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Young Researchers Workshop 2019</title><link href="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/SPICE-workshop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Young Researchers Workshop 2019" /><published>2019-09-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-09-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/SPICE-workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.skyrmionics.ph.nat.tum.de/SPICE-workshop/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="17---19-september-2019-university-of-mainz">17 - 19 September 2019, University of Mainz</h4>

<p>A young researchers workshop on Skyrmionics organized by PhD students and Postdocs participating in the priority program SPP2137 took place at the Spin Phenomena Interdisciplinary Center (SPICE) at the University of Mainz. The workshop started with tutorials and an introduction to topology in in physics and skyrmions in general, followed by talks focused on the most recent advances in Skyrmionics. The program of the workshop may be found <a href="https://www.spice.uni-mainz.de/spp_program/">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="past" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[17 - 19 September 2019, University of Mainz A young researchers workshop on Skyrmionics organized by PhD students and Postdocs participating in the priority program SPP2137 took place at the Spin Phenomena Interdisciplinary Center (SPICE) at the University of Mainz. The workshop started with tutorials and an introduction to topology in in physics and skyrmions in general, followed by talks focused on the most recent advances in Skyrmionics. The program of the workshop may be found here.]]></summary></entry></feed>